<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Ivy League Free Courses</title><link>https://www.classcentral.com</link><description>Latest free courses from Ivy League universities</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 04:27:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Terrible Swift Sword: Confederate Ascendency and Ultimate Defeat - Class 14</title><link>https://www.classcentral.com/classroom/youtube-class14-terrible-swift-sword-confederate-ascendency-and-ultimate-defeat-364855</link><description>&lt;class&gt;Ivy_League_Course&lt;/class&gt;
&lt;hash&gt;b5f142c&lt;/hash&gt;
Explore the pivotal moments of Confederate military success and eventual downfall during the Civil War, examining their lasting impact on American society and constitutional framework.</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 01:50:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Never Call Retreat: Military Turning Points and Why the North Won the Civil War - Class 15</title><link>https://www.classcentral.com/classroom/youtube-class15-never-call-retreat-military-turning-points-and-why-the-north-won-the-war-364854</link><description>&lt;class&gt;Ivy_League_Course&lt;/class&gt;
&lt;hash&gt;3c5f473&lt;/hash&gt;
Explore the pivotal military turning points of the Civil War and analyze the strategic factors that led to the Union's victory, examining the war's lasting impact on American society.</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 01:35:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Plastic in Our Blood: Understanding Health Impacts of Microplastic Exposure</title><link>https://www.classcentral.com/classroom/youtube-plastic-in-our-blood-that-s-a-problem-355556</link><description>&lt;class&gt;Ivy_League_Course&lt;/class&gt;
&lt;hash&gt;c34f6ed&lt;/hash&gt;
Explore the alarming presence of microplastics in human bodies, their health implications, and our complex relationship with plastic pollution through expert insights and research findings.</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 20:03:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Causes of the American Civil War: Slavery, States' Rights, and the Irrepressible Conflict - Class 13</title><link>https://www.classcentral.com/classroom/youtube-class-13-irrepressible-or-needless-slavery-or-states-rights-what-caused-the-civil-war-354984</link><description>&lt;class&gt;Ivy_League_Course&lt;/class&gt;
&lt;hash&gt;c634607&lt;/hash&gt;
Explore the complex historical debate over Civil War causation, examining the roles of slavery, states' rights, and political tensions in shaping America's deadliest conflict.</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 19:48:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>No Rights: Dred Scott, Bleeding Kansas, and the Impending Crisis of the Union - Class 11</title><link>https://www.classcentral.com/classroom/youtube-class-11-no-rights-dred-scott-bleeding-kansas-and-the-impending-crisis-of-the-union-353334</link><description>&lt;class&gt;Ivy_League_Course&lt;/class&gt;
&lt;hash&gt;a17ae76&lt;/hash&gt;
Explore the pivotal events of Dred Scott, Bleeding Kansas, and the impending crisis leading to the Civil War. Gain insights into slavery's impact on American institutions and its enduring legacies.</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 19:33:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>John Brown's Holy War, 1860 Election, and the Secession Crisis - Class 12</title><link>https://www.classcentral.com/classroom/youtube-class12-john-brown-s-holy-war-1860-election-and-the-secession-crisis-353333</link><description>&lt;class&gt;Ivy_League_Course&lt;/class&gt;
&lt;hash&gt;c5dd2f0&lt;/hash&gt;
Explore the pivotal events leading to the Civil War: John Brown's raid, the 1860 election, and the secession crisis. Gain insights into slavery's impact on American history and its enduring legacies.</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 19:18:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Structure and Function of Argument: Introduction to Critical Thinking</title><link>https://www.classcentral.com/course/philosophy-ethics-harvard-university-structure-an-353078</link><description>&lt;class&gt;Ivy_League_Course&lt;/class&gt;
&lt;hash&gt;9f0544f&lt;/hash&gt;
Explore the underlying structures of everyday arguments and develop the tools to communicate effectively.</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 19:03:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Case for a Liberal Arts Education: Is It Worth the Investment?</title><link>https://www.classcentral.com/classroom/youtube-the-case-for-a-liberal-arts-education-350256</link><description>&lt;class&gt;Ivy_League_Course&lt;/class&gt;
&lt;hash&gt;45afa1d&lt;/hash&gt;
Explore the value and relevance of liberal arts education in today's world, examining its benefits, challenges, and potential for personal and societal growth.</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 01:20:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>"Mexico Will Poison Us": War of Conquest, the Compromise, and Kansas-Nebraska - Class 10</title><link>https://www.classcentral.com/classroom/youtube-class10-mexico-will-poison-us-war-of-conquest-the-compromise-and-kansas-nebraska-350090</link><description>&lt;class&gt;Ivy_League_Course&lt;/class&gt;
&lt;hash&gt;aee095c&lt;/hash&gt;
Explore the Mexican-American War's impact on slavery, the Compromise of 1850, and the Kansas-Nebraska Act in shaping American history and institutions.</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 18:33:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Psychology, Biology and Politics of Food - Lecture 6</title><link>https://www.classcentral.com/classroom/youtube-the-psychology-biology-and-politics-of-food-06-348801</link><description>&lt;class&gt;Ivy_League_Course&lt;/class&gt;
&lt;hash&gt;512adaa&lt;/hash&gt;
Explore the intricate connections between psychology, biology, and politics in relation to food systems and consumption patterns.</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 18:18:04 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>